Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1840-2010; Accession 2011-M-063
  - Family papers
    - John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney family
      - Whitney, John Hay
        - Biographical
          - Military service records
            - Capture, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 5)
            - Legion of Merit, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 6)
            - Maps, Circa 1943 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence (incoming)
          - Haddad, Andrea, 1976-1990, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
          - Haddad, Camilla, 1978, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
          - Haddad, Laura, 1976-1984 (Box 19, Folder 10)
          - Henry, Barklie, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 11)
          - New York Herald Tribune, 1942-1949, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
          - Payson, Joan Whitney, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 13)
          - Philanthropy, 1932-1944 (Box 19, Folder 14)
          - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, 1942-1945, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
          - Whitney, Kate Roosevelt and Sara Roosevelt, Undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
          - Unidentified, 1961, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Whitney, John Hay and Betsey Cushing correspondence (incoming)
        - Balding, Gerald, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Baragwanath, Jack, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Barnes, Janet and Tracy, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Christmas cards, 1950-1957 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
        - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and Mamie, 1957-1968, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - Elliot, Katharine, Baroness Elliot of Harwood, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 8)
        - Grandchildren, 1968-1978, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
        - Guion, Connie, 1959-1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - Johnson, Marie, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - Jones, Anthony Armstrong (Royal family), Undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
        - Montagu, Judith, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 13)
        - New York Herald Tribune, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        - Payson family, Undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
        - Sitwell, Edith, Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
        - Spivack, Sydney, 1950, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 17)
        - Straight family, Undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
        - Symington family, 1957-1960 (Box 20, Folder 19)
        - Whitney, Kate, 1946-1954, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
        - Wilford, Sara Roosevelt, 1947, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
        - Wisner, Frank, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 22)
        - Unidentified, Undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Roosevelt, Sara and Kate correspondence from Franklin Delano and Eleanor Roosevelt, 1938, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Whitney, Kate Roosevelt correspondence from Maud O'Shea Herlihy, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Topical
        - Fine Art Collection
          - Appraisals
            - General, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 1)
            - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, 1982-1998 (Box 21, Folder 2-5)
          - Art loans, 1994-1998 (Box 21, Folder 6)
          - Artists
            - Bellows, George, 1950-1998 (Box 21, Folder 7)
            - Braque, Georges, 1951-1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
            - Cézanne, Paul, 1948-1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
            - Cross, Henri Edmond, 1950-1983 (Box 22, Folder 3)
            - Dufy, Raoul, 1951-1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
            - Marquet, Albert, 1977-1990 (Box 22, Folder 5)
            - Matisse, Henri, 1956-1991 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
            - Monet, Claude, 1949-1989 (Box 22, Folder 8)
            - Picasso, Pablo, 1949-1998 (Box 22, Folder 9)
            - Signac, Paul, 1950-1989 (Box 22, Folder 10)
            - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri
              - General (correspondence), 1950-1998 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
              - Chilpéric
                - Appraisal, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 3)
                - Correspondence, 1990-1997 (Box 23, Folder 4)
                - Deed of gift to National Gallery of Art, 1990-1996 (Box 23, Folder 5)
                - Loan agreement, 1983-1991 (Box 23, Folder 6)
                - Publications, 1989-1995 (Box 23, Folder 7)
                - Research, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
            - Van Dongen, Kees, 1960-1983 (Box 24, Folder 1)
            - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1947-1998 (Box 24, Folder 2-4)
            - Vlaminck, Maurice De, 1950-1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
          - Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 1)
          - Insurance, 1982-1986, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 2)
          - Paintings
            - Betsey Cushing Whitney estate, 1994-2008 (Box 25, Folder 3)
            - John Hay Whitney estate, 1983-1986 (Box 25, Folder 4)
          - Room 4600 (Whitney family office)
            - General, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
            - Correspondence (Museum of Modern Art), 1977-1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - Greentree Foundation, 1987-1992 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Greenwood Fund, Circa 1946 (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - New York Herald Tribune
          - General, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 3)
          - McKinsey report, 1961-1962 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
        - Properties
          - 972 Fifth Avenue
            - Venetian Room
              - Appraisal, 1948-1997 (Box 26, Folder 6)
              - Awards, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
              - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 8)
              - French Embassy, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 9)
              - Gala, 1998 April 8 (Box 26, Folder 10)
              - Mount Ida Press, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 11-12)
              - Reception, 1998 April 17 (Box 26, Folder 13)
              - Reinstallation, 1997-2010 (Box 26, Folder 14)
          - East 63rd Street, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Payne Whitney and Helen Hay Whitney Family correspondence (incoming)
      - Payson, Joan Whitney, from Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Whitney, Flora Payne, from Henry W. Payne, 1876 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Whitney, Helen Hay
        - General, 1899-1936, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Roosevelt, Theodore and Edith, 1901, 1910, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Whitney, Payne
        - Family, 1903-1905, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Financial, 1903-1918 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Whitney, Helen Hay, 1901-1906, undated (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
        - Whitney, William Collins, condolences on death of, 1904 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - Unidentified, 1904-1925 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Harvey Cushing and Kate Crowell Cushing Family
      - Clippings
        - 1917-1958 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Crowell, Mary Benedict
        - Address book
          - 1912 (Box 28, Folder 3)
          - 1926 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence from grandchildren, 1914-1917 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Diary, 1902-1909 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Cushing, Harvey
        - Biographical
          - General, 1920-1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
            - Oversize, Undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
          - Articles about
            - General, 1974-1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
            - By friends and colleagues, 1987-1992 (Box 29, Folder 3)
            - From Surgery Magazine about, 1983-1986 (Box 29, Folder 4)
          - Biographies, 1950-1980 (Box 29, Folder 5)
          - Birthday remembrances, 1940-1970 (Box 29, Folder 6)
          - Book collection, 1939-1991 (Box 29, Folder 7)
          - Cemetery
            - Information, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 8)
            - Pamphlets, 1978, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
            - Plot maps and layouts, Undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
          - Cushing stamp, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 11)
          - Estate, Undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
          - Family crest, Undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
          - Friendship with William Osler, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 14)
          - Hartford Medical Society, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 15)
          - Harvard/Massachusetts General Hospital, 1920-1949 (Box 29, Folder 16)
          - Harvey Cushing Hospital dedication, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 17)
          - Johns Hopkins University professorship, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 18)
          - New York Hospital professorship, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 19)
          - North Shore Hospital lectureship, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 20)
          - Obituaries, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 21)
          - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, Undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
          - Purgatorian Society, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 23)
            - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 2)
          - Wedding to Kate Crowell Cushing, 1902 (Box 29, Folder 24)
          - Will, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 1)
          - Writings
            - "An Episode in the Life of Mr. Ferguson", Undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
            - Notes, Undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
            - Questions and answers, Undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
          - Yale Medical Library, Harvey Cushing inventories, 1987-1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
          - Yale University professorship, 1970-1988 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence
          - Incoming
            - Astor, Vincent, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 1)
            - Crowell, Mary, 1902, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 2)
            - Cushing family, 1902-1918, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
            - Cushing, Betsey Maria (sister), 1888 (Box 31, Folder 4)
            - Cushing, Bill, 1915-1924, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
            - Cushing, Henry, 1918-1928 (Box 31, Folder 6)
            - Cushing, Kate Crowell (wife), 1898-1936, undated (Box 31, Folder 7-13)
            - Engagement to Kate Crowell Cushing, 1902 (Box 31, Folder 14)
            - Fosburgh, Mary Cushing (daughter), 1911-1929 (Box 32, Folder 1)
            - Germain, Karl, 1917-1939 (Box 32, Folder 2)
            - Goodwillie, Mary, 1917-1918 (Box 32, Folder 3)
            - Osler, William, 1903 (Box 32, Folder 4)
            - Paley, Barbara (Babe) Cushing, 1918-1923 (Box 32, Folder 5)
            - Roosevelt family, 1929, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
            - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1929-2000 (Box 32, Folder 7)
              Includes photocopies of letters from Franklin Delano Roosevelt to Dr. Harvey Cushing from the Franklin D. Roosevelt Presidential Library and Museum given to Kate Roosevelt Whitney by Doris Kearns Goodwin.
            - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, 1916-1929 (Box 32, Folder 8)
            - Unidentified, 1897-1923 (Box 32, Folder 9)
          - Outgoing
            - Cushing, William, Undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Cushing, Kate Crowell
        - Biographical
          - General, Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
          - Christmas list, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 2)
          - Date book
            - 1930 (Box 33, Folder 3)
            - 1935 (Box 33, Folder 4)
          - Diaries
            - 1897 (Box 33, Folder 5)
            - 1902 (Box 33, Folder 6)
              Chronicles wedding to Harvey Cushing.
            - 1913-1919 (Box 33, Folder 7)
            - 1928 (Box 33, Folder 8)
            - 1940 (Box 34, Folder 1)
            - 1945-1950 (Box 34, Folder 2)
          - Hobe Sound reflections, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 3)
          - Household accounts, 1901-1908 (Box 34, Folder 4)
          - Knitting instructions, Undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
          - Memorial service, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 6)
          - Poems, Undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
          - Wedding presents, 1902 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence
          - Incoming
            - Bobbie, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 1)
            - Calling cards, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 2)
            - Crowell, Mary, 1909-1917, undated (Box 35, Folder 3-7)
            - Cushing, Bill, 1915-1927 (Box 35, Folder 8)
            - Cushing, Harvey, 1902-1927 (Box 35, Folder 9)
            - Death of Harvey Cushing, condolences
              - 1939 October 7 (Box 36, Folder 1)
              - 1939 October 8 (Box 36, Folder 2)
              - 1939 October 9 (Box 36, Folder 3)
              - 1939 October 10 (Box 36, Folder 4)
              - 1939 October 11 (Box 37, Folder 1)
              - 1939 October 12 (Box 37, Folder 2)
              - 1939 October 13-16 (Box 37, Folder 3)
              - 1939 October 17-30 (Box 37, Folder 4)
              - 1939 November 1-19 (Box 37, Folder 5)
              - 1939 November-1940 October (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
            - Engagement to Harvey Cushing, congratulations, 1902 (Box 38, Folder 1)
            - Friends, 1918-1939 (Box 38, Folder 2)
            - Fosburgh, Mary, 1919-1949, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
            - Fulton, John, 1931 (Box 38, Folder 4)
            - Grandchildren, Undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
            - Paley, Barbara, 1918-1923, 1940 (Box 38, Folder 6)
            - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1937-1941 (Box 38, Folder 7)
            - Thomas, Charles, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 8)
            - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
              - 1916-1924 (Box 38, Folder 9)
              - 1925 (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
              - 1926-1938 (Box 39, Folder 1)
            - Whitney, John Hay, Undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
            - Yale Historical Library (Yale School of Medicine), 1940-1969 (Box 39, Folder 3)
          - Outgoing
            - Webb, Watson, Undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Cushing, Kate Crowell and Harvey correspondence
        - Crowell, Mary Benedict, Undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - Crowell, William, 1925 (Box 39, Folder 6)
        - Cushing, Kate, Undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - Cushing, William, Undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Goodcollie, Mary, Undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Fosburgh, Mary Cushing
        - Diary, 1927 (Box 39, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence
          - Cushing, Kate Crowell, death of, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 11)
          - Cushing, Kate Crowell, illness, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 12)
          - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, Undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
          - Worth, Irene, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 14)
        - Writings, 1925 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - Paley, Barbara (Babe) Cushing (correspondence)
        - Death of Kate Crowell Cushing, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 16-19)
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, Undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Eleanor Roosevelt Family
      - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
        - Estate, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Presidential Library cornerstone ceremony, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 2)
        - Press releases, 1932-1939 (Box 40, Folder 3)
        - Speech, motion picture industry, 1941 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Roosevelt, James
        - Clippings, 1929-1952, undated (Box 40, Folder 5-6)
        - Correspondence
          - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1931, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
          - Roosevelt, Sara Delano, 1929, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
        - Speech, Alfred E. Smith endorsement, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Photographs
    Boxes 48-51 contain oversized photographs; boxes 52-55 contain encased ambrotypes and daguerreotypes.
    - Families/Individuals
      - Crowell, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Cushing
        - General, Undated (Box 41, Folder 2-3)
          - Ambrotypes and daguerreotypes (unidentified)
            - Child, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 53, Folder 5)
            - Male child, Circa 1840-1880 (Box 54, Folder 8)
            - Male child with cloak, Circa 1840-1880 (Box 53, Folder 4)
            - Man with ascot, Circa 1840-1880 (Box 53, Folder 3)
            - Woman seated by table, Circa 1840-1880 (Box 54, Folder 7)
            - Woman standing with unidentified man, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 55, Folder 4)
            - Women, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 53, Folder 6-9)
          - Oversize, Circa 1890-1920 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
        - Briggs, Cornelia (Cushing), Circa 1840-1880 (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Cushing sisters (Barbara, Betsey and Mary), 1920-1960 (Box 41, Folder 4)
        - Cushing, Alice K., Circa 1860-1880 (Box 52, Folder 6-7)
        - Cushing, Harvey, Undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
          - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Cushing, Harvey and Kate Crowell, Undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
        - Cushing, Henry Kirke (Betsey Cushing Whitney's brother), Circa 1910-1920 (Box 41, Folder 7)
        - Cushing, Kate Crowell, Circa 1890-1940 (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Cushing, M. B., Circa 1860-1880 (Box 55, Folder 2)
        - Cushing, Mary Ann (Pratt), Circa 1840-1880 (Box 52, Folder 8)
        - Cushing, Nellie Cornelia, 1857-1859 (Box 54, Folder 9)
          - Ambrotypes (Box 55, Folder 5-7)
          - Daguerreotype, 1857-1859 (Box 55, Folder 9)
          - Tintype, 1857-1859 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Cushing, W. E., Circa 1860-1880 (Box 52, Folder 9)
          - Ambrotypes (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
        - Cushing, William David, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 52, Folder 5)
        - Cushing, William Harvey (Betsey Cushing Whitney's brother), Circa 1903-1925 (Box 41, Folder 9)
          - Oversize, Undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - Fitch, Zalman, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Fosburgh, Mary Cushing, Circa 1906-1960 (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - Friends, 1890-1940 (Box 42, Folder 2)
        - Harvey, Mr., Circa 1860-1880 (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - Kirke, Circa 1840-1860 (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Kirke, Dr., Circa 1860-1880 (Box 54, Folder 2-4)
        - Mead, Stephen (Betsey Cushing Whitney's great-grandfather), Circa 1860-1880 (Box 54, Folder 5)
        - Paley, Barbara, 1915-1960 (Box 42, Folder 3)
          - Oversize (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Pratt, Charlotte (Mead), Circa 1840-1880 (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Williams (Harvey Cushing's maternal family)
          - George, Circa 1840-1880 (Box 55, Folder 3)
          - Martha Porter, Circa 1860-1880 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Roosevelt
        - General, 1932-1940 (Box 42, Folder 4)
        - Wedding, James Roosevelt and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1930 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Whitney
        - Payson, Joan Whitney, Circa 1902-1940 (Box 42, Folder 5-6)
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
          - General, Circa 1908-1990 (Box 42, Folder 7-8)
            - Oversize (Box 51, Folder 5)
          - Ambassadorial, 1957-1961 (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing and John Hay
          - General, 1942-1952 (Box 42, Folder 10)
          - Ambassadorial, Circa 1957-1961 (Box 42, Folder 11)
            - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 5)
          - Greentree photo shoot, Circa 1957-1961 (Box 42, Folder 12)
        - Whitney, Helen Hay
          - General, Circa 1880-1930 (Box 42, Folder 13)
          - Friends, 1890-1900 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
        - Whitney, John Hay
          - General, Circa 1904-1960 (Box 43, Folder 3)
            - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 4)
          - Ambassadorial
            - General, 1957-1961 (Box 43, Folder 4)
              - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 6)
            - Christmas party - American Embassy, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 5)
            - MacMillan, Harold, 1961 February 15 (Box 43, Folder 6)
            - Presentation of letter of credence, 1957 February 28 (Box 43, Folder 7)
            - Queen Mother Elizabeth visit, Circa 1957-1961 (Box 43, Folder 8)
            - Royal Air Force, Brize Norton visit, 1960 September 14 (Box 43, Folder 9)
            - Sandringham, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 10)
            - "U.S. Envoy Family at Home", 1957 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - Army
            - General, 1942-1945 (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
            - After escape, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 4)
        - Whitney, Payne and Helen Hay Family, Circa 1900-1930 (Box 44, Folder 5)
        - Williams (Harvey Williams Cushing maternal), Circa 1870-1890 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Topical
      - General, 1930-1970 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Aphrodite (yacht), 1951 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Astaire, Fred, at Greentree, Circa 1960-1970 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Birthday parties
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, Circa 1960 (Box 44, Folder 10)
        - Whitney, John Hay, Undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Cherry Hill, 1958 August 17 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Cushing stamp
        - Ceremony, 1987 April 8 (Box 44, Folder 13)
        - Unveiling, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Fishers Island, Circa 1950-1960 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Florida Keys, Circa 1950-1960 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Friends, Undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Hobe Sound, Circa 1950-1960 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Horses, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital founding, 1989 September 24 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Properties
        - 305 Walnut Street, Brookline, Massachusetts, 1912-1913 (Box 45, Folder 6)
        - Bolton house, 1925 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Greentree, Manhasset, New York, Circa 1990 (Box 45, Folder 8)
        - Greentree Stud and Stable, Lexington, Kentucky, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 45, Folder 9)
        - Little Boar's Head, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 45, Folder 10)
          - Oversize (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Royal family, Circa 1957-1961 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Tate Gallery, John Hay Whitney Collection opening, 1960 December 16 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 46, Folder 1-5)
        - Oversize (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbooks/Photograph albums
    - Cushing family scrapbook, Circa 1895-1905 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Cushing family photograph album (oversize), Circa 1900-1920 (Box 48)
    - "Great Americans" series stamp honoring Dr. Harvey Cushing, Undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Harvey Cushing and Johns Hopkins, 1896-1912, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Milton Academy, 1918 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Includes clippings and maps from William Harvey Cushing's years as a student.
    - White House years, 1932-1940 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Includes clippings from Betsey Cushing Whitney's years in Washington during the Roosevelt administration.